MATTHEW LIVINGSTONE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Profile

Versatile developer with 8+ years of experience including front-end and back-end web development, mobile applications, micro-controllers, and desktop applications. Involved in the requirement analysis, architecture/design, development, quality assurance, implementation and release of software products.

Technical

HTML5	.Net / C#	Java / Android SDK
CSS	PHP	Business Objects / Webl / IDT
Angular / Vue / React	Subversion / Git	Windows / Linux (Debian) / OS X

Experience

BESTECH

2012 - Present

Developer

- Built hybrid mobile applications, as well as a new online console and web API for the Electrical Safety Authority as part of their e-WorkSAFE platform
- Extensive Business Objects experience using WebIntelligence, Information Design Tool, and light work with Crystal Reports
- SharePoint 2013 management
- Helped design and build enhancements to NRG1-ECO Ventilation Control Software

Sunwire Inc.

2010 - 2012

Developer

- One of the lead developers for their private branch exchange (PBX) system, SolSwitch which was based on Asterisk and a PHP back-end
- Wrote firmware for PIC micro-controllers that allowed the controller to interface with Toothpick Bluetooth chipsets, and in-turn the ability to communicate with Blackberry devices over Bluetooth
- Wrote Blackberry application that acts as an intermediary between the PIC/Toothpick hardware and server
- PIC and Toothpick hardware was installed in vehicles and ensured the vehicles could only be operated by authorized employees
- Wrote firmware for PIC micro-controller that was combined with other hardware, and used to detect Rapid Eye Movement (R.E.M.) sleep. The firmware also included basic Human Interface Device driver identification.

(Notable) Personal Projects

2008 - Present

- Plugin-based Telegram bot running on Node.js on a private VPS
- Source server RCON application for Android, using a remote server for NAT punch-through
- Cityapp.ca

MIRARCO 2008 - 2009

Developer

- Developer on mining data visualization application, ParaViewGeo
- Wrote and expanded multiple plugins for ParaViewGeo
- Setup and maintained build machines to test ParaViewGeo

Education

Laurentian University - Sudbury, Ontario

Bachelor of Computer Science, with Honours (H.B.COSC.)

Matthew Livingstone — mmrlivingstone@gmail.com